A Guide to the Warren A. McNeill Papers, 1928-1984
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Warren A. McNeill Papers, 1928-1984
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 213-273
.5 linear feet
Warren A. McNeill
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to Special Collections and Archives by Mr. McNeill in June 1989.
Biographical/Historical Information
Warren Albert McNeill (1903-1998) was born in Brockton, Mass. in 1903, grew up in Lynchburg, Va., and received B.A. and M.A. degrees from the University of Richmond. He was a reporter for the Lynchburg News and the Richmond Times-Dispatch in the mid-1920s where he served as city editor before becoming a member of the Associated Press staff in 1930. In 1947 he left AP to become Administrative Assistant to Senator A. Willis Robertson of Virginia. He later moved to Kentucky and became Director of Public Relations and Advertising for the Louisville and Nashville Railroad in 1960, and retired in 1970.
McNeill began corresponding with Richmond writer James Branch Cabell in 1924 when he was writing for the book page in the Lynchburg News. He wrote Cabellian Harmonics, a study of the works of Cabell which published in 1928. He also wrote Cabell book reviews for Lynchburg, Richmond, and Nashville newspapers, and a stage adaptation of "In Ursula's Garden" entitled "The Masque." In the 1970s he wrote a number of articles on Cabell published in two journals devoted to Cabell, The Cabellian and Kalki.
He was a former president of the Railroad Public Relations Association and was recognized as Kentucky's first fully accredited member of the Public Relations Society of America. He died July 19, 1998 in Lexington, Kentucky.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence, manuscripts, newspaper clippings, periodicals, and miscellany relating to McNeill's Cabell studies.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Contents List
- American Mercury, Dec. 1951 (Box-folder 1.1)
- Articles, reviews by McNeill on Cabell, n.d. 1931-1939 (Box-folder 1.2)
- The Cabellian: correspondence, manuscripts of articles 1930-1932, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 1.3)
- Cabellian Harmonics: correspondence 1928 (Box-folder 1.4)
- Cabellian Harmonics: manuscripts 1928 (Box-folder 1.5)
- Carolina Quarterly, Spring 1962 (Box-folder 1.6)
- Correspondence with James Branch Cabell 1924-1957 (Box-folder 1.7)
- Kalki: correspondence with editors 1968-1984 (Box-folder 1.8)
- The Masque 1926 (Box-folder 1.9)
- Miscellaneous materials on James Branch Cabell 1929-1963 (Box-folder 1.10)